lizo knows exactly what she
wants and lizo held us to the
standard making every Melody and every
lyric exactly what she wanted to
[Music]
say hi I'm Ricky Reid and I'm Blake
slatkin we're here with mix with the
Masters at Westlake Studio D discussing
lizo about damn time it's about damn
time in a minute I'mma need a
sentimental man or woman to pump me up
the E minor 9 is this really cool chord
that omits the
third I remember you hitting that cord
and I was like wa so you have this chord
the third is usually the thing that
tells you do I feel happy or do I feel
sad honestly I think it lays a great
groundwork for a song Where lizo could
be hopeful at times upset frustrated
whatever Turn Up the Music turn down the
lights before she even sang she just
said no tune no Reverb no delay dry
which is brave and very hard to do cuz
kind of tune and Reverb and all those
things are kind of the training wheels
it's all these things to make you feel
better about your performance and she
just takes it all off and she just like
I'm going to get the
performance
[Music]
alln I think what was really neat was
when we were like wait what if the pre
chorus is the guitar
rhythm
but we just pull out that downbeat of
ooh ooh ooh so the precourse is just uh
uh uh uh but it's the same uh uh uh as
the verses which kind of disorients you
in kind of the perfect way when you get
back to the hook it's like ah it's about
damn
[Music]
time Perfect
part I remember watching you program
that I love it cuz it's kind of fluty
it's a little bit flu before we even had
lizzo's flute on it very reminiscent of
early like BOS skag stuff and all the
flute that you love on Disco records but
a little bit more cynthy it just has its
own character that I love I'm going be
okay
okay all
it's the drums I think I think it's that
one shot of the snare mhm I think I
tried like 50 different Lin kicks to see
which one was sampled the best through
whatever cuz you know every like sample
pack people do different stuff to like
process the things so I think we tried a
bunch of different kicks I can't
remember do we have a kick a live kick
layer in that or no no this is just a
sample kick it's just sample kick so
it's the classic the classic ly works
every
[Music]
time my favorite records mix modern and
and old and I love how some of it's live
and some of it's very drum machiney and
it kind of makes this perfect kind of
family
that it doesn't belong to any era
really something else from that day that
I think is a really cool thing that is
hard to hear is that voder so I did one
day uh with Terrace Martin in here which
was a blast he's the greatest great dear
friend super Talent there was a few
parts that actually made the record
they're sort of they're in the second
pre chorus I guess what is that yeah
let's hear those real quick these are
really
neat let's hear that with her
singing I'm Not the girl I was or used
to be just again just these amazing
amazing little bits that move the record
along that Push It Forward get up get
down that's how I feel right now on this
song definitely was a case where the
master bus is bar involved it's not
affecting how you know things pump
there's like no pumping there's not a
lot of effect as far as like the gluing
and what there isn't a lot of glue on it
yeah it's almost like an eqing sort of
sweetener that makes it a little bit
louder I'm the
[Music]
girl it's so funny listening back cuz
everything sounds so simple I mean
obviously anyone making records realizes
that the simplest stuff is the hardest
to do there's so much DNA lying under
the things that you've been so
conditioned to to hear and know and I
know both of us listen to so much disco
and so much funk all all that stuff and
there's so many little tiny things that
make each record what it is I think we
just had to spend all that time getting
the pocket perfect and making a about
damn time what it
is turn
the Turn Down the
Lights I
got we were trying to make the first
single on the album and that was the
whole kind of goal she held us to the
standard where I was like we are going
to make every single part of this the
best it can be there were so many
rewrites there were so many there were
months and months and months of making
every Melody and every lyric exactly
what she wanted to
[Music]
say tonight I'm coming out
tonight part of her appeal is feeling
like you're sitting next to her feeling
like you can relate to her it's the
human touch and for me the more you know
layers of
effects and whatnot you just lose more
and more of what makes her
special